# **BRIAN HASAL**

Las Vegas, NV | brian.hasal@gmail.com | 818-800-0019 | github.com/brianhasal | linkedin.com/in/brianhasal/

# **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

I have made the transition to web development, after a twenty-year career as a stage manager for large-scale musical theater productions. Returning to an early passion for PC building and programming, I genuinely enjoy maximizing efficiency in complex organizational structures, learning new programming languages, facilitating group cohesion, and engaging in decisive problem-solving.

#### SKILLS

**Technical:** Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C#, Python, React.js, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, APIs, Pair-Programming, Databases, Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap, REST

Additional: American Sign Language (conversational), File Maker Pro, Vegas Video, Adobe Photoshop

### **EDUCATION**

# **Actualize Coding Bootcamp**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development | March 2022 - July 2022

- Marvel Puzzle Quest Companion: Personally designed and built a web app that utilizes a Ruby on Rails backend to allow verified users to recreate and save their rosters from Marvel Puzzle Quest. The app improves upon the in-game content by utilizing the Marvel Comics API to provide a more comprehensive view of the character, including links to sites that provide source material, while adding a comment component to discuss builds/pairings with other users.
- **Bootcamp:** Learned fundamentals and best practices in full stack web development in areas of project architecture, back end, front end, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
  - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
  - o Built and tested the back end, incorporating external APIs
  - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes

California State University, Northridge Bachelor of Arts in Theater (2001)

### **EXPERIENCE**

Disney Theatrical Productions | July 2015 - September 2021

Assistant Stage Manager | "The Lion King - Rafiki Tour" | August 2017 - September 2021

- Devised a remapping of backstage traffic for multiple departments, which yielded a comprehensive user database, to allow greater versatility in performance-space options. This process allowed for Disney to book the show into a wider variety of markets, increasing revenue in previously unusable parts of the country.
- Overhauled outdated systems of preparation to expedite load-in times by creating a database of venue statistics, photos and explicit instructions for new and previously-visited venues.
- During the first 987 performances, I established the baseline process by which my job was done, while this
  production was being built. The specifics of my specialty are still being used by an entirely new staff, and live in
  perpetuity.
- Fifth time I have been hired by Disney for various long-term contracts.

# Assistant Stage Manager | "The Lion King - Gazelle Tour" | July 2015 - August 2017

- Supervised the international production for final 1000 performances of the 15-year national tour, with a staff of 125 employees, over 8 departments all of whom move to a new city every 2-4 weeks.
- Instituted a new purchasing policy for equipment that proved more accurate, faster, and less expensive than the previous system.
- Brought in to replace previous managers and reconfigured communications within staff to restore collaboration and reduce friction between departments, making for more effective processes and increasing employee satisfaction.

# Production Manager | "JabbaWockeeZ: Prism" | Luxor Hotel & Casino | March, 2014 - July, 2015

- Supervised entire technical (15) and performing (30) staffs in a solo management position, for 700+ performances
- Refactored management responsibilities to allow for completion of a greater variety of tasks in less time
- Revised payment structure for performing company
- Stocked all manner of show needs with multiple vendors across several states
- Trained new staff on how to safely perform on moving/automated scenery